Herbert Elliston Papers
Herbert Elliston Papers
1940-1957
Elliston, Herbert Berridge.
5 linear ft.
American journalist, Pulitzer Prize winner. Collection consists entirely of clippings of Elliston's editorials.
2744157
Biographical History
Herbert Elliston (1895-1957) was an American journalist, winner of the 1949 Pulitzer Prize for Distinguished Editorial Writing. Born in England, Elliston served in the Royal Horse Artillery and subsequently was foreign correspondent for a number of British newspapers. Around 1920 he took a position as foreign correspondent with the New York Herald; he later began to write editorials for that publication. From 1930 to 1940 he was financial editor and columnist for the Christian Science Monitor, and from 1940-1953 he was editorial page editor for the Washington Post. After his retirement in 1953, he continued to write a regular Sunday column for the Post until his death.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Herbert Elliston Papers consist entirely of clippings of his editorials, spanning nearly twenty years.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is unprocessed and remains in original order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Elliston, Herbert Berridge.; American newspapers -- Sections, columns, etc. -- Editorials.; Editorials -- United States.; Journalists -- United States.; Newspaper editors -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Files (document groupings); Newspaper editors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Herbert Elliston, 1964.
Inventory
- Writings
  - Editorials, 1940, Nov; clippings (Box 1)
  - Editorials, 1941, Jan-Dec; clippings; 12 folders (Box 1)
  - Editorials, 1942, Jan-Dec; clippings; 12 folders (Box 2)
  - Editorials, 1943, Jan-Jun; clippings; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Editorials, 1943, Jul-Dec; clippings (Box 3)
  - Editorials, 1944, Jan-Dec; clippings; 12 folders (Box 3)
  - Editorials, 1945, Jan-Dec; clippings; 12 folders (Box 4)
  - Editorials, 1946, Jan-Mar; clippings; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Editorials, 1946, Apr-Dec; clippings; 9 folders (Box 5)
  - Editorials, 1947, Jan-Jul; clippings; 7 folders (Box 5)
  - Editorials, 1947, Aug-Dec; clippings; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Editorials, 1948, Jan-Dec; clippings; 12 folders (Box 6)
  - Editorials, 1949, Jan-Dec; clippings; 12 folders (Box 7)
  - Editorials, 1950, Jan-Jul; clippings; 7 folders (Box 7)
  - Editorials, 1950, Aug-Dec; clippings (Box 8)
  - Editorials, 1951, Jan-Dec; clippings; 12 folders (Box 8)
  - Editorials, 1952, Jan-May; clippings; 5 folders (Box 8)
  - Editorials, 1952, Jul, Oct-Dec; clippings; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Editorials, 1953, Jan-Oct; clippings; 10 folders (Box 9)
  - Editorials, 1954, Feb-Dec; clippings; 11 folders (Box 9)
  - Editorials, 1955, Jan-Dec; clippings; 12 folders (Box 10)
  - Editorials, 1956, Jan-Dec; clippings; 12 folders (Box 10)
  - Editorials, 1957, Jan; clippings (Box 10)